Finding Aid of the UW-Milwaukee Office of the Chancellor Records, 1933-2014
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
- Records, 1933-2011, UWM Archival Collection 46; 220.4 cubic ft. (224 boxes) 2 film reels 718 digital files (539 MB)
  - 7. Santiago Administration Records, 2000-2011
    - Subject Files, 2000-2011
      - Kenwood Interdisciplinary Research Complex Environmental Impact Statement
        - Draft, 2011 (Box 187, Folder 5)
        - Final Report, 2011 (Box 187, Folder 6)
      - Klotsche Center
        - 2005-2010 (Box 197, Folder 63)
        - Renovation, 2010 (Box 197, Folder 64)
      - Legal Affairs, 2005-2009 (Box 203, Folder 3)
      - Legislators Correspondence, 2003-2011 (Box 198, Folder 1-2)
      - Letters and Science, College of, 2004-2010 (Box 198, Folder 3)
      - Library, 2004-2010 (Box 198, Folder 4-5)
      - Life Impact Program of UWM, Evaluation, 2010 (Box 198, Folder 6)
      - Lubar (Sheldon B.) School of Business, 2003-2010 (Box 198, Folder 7)
      - Manpower, 2003-2004 (Box 198, Folder 8)
      - Marquette University, 2008-2009 (Box 198, Folder 9)
      - Master Plan, 2010
      - Mayor's Office, 2004-2011 (Box 198, Folder 10)
      - Medical College of Wisconsin, 2004-2010 (Box 198, Folder 11)
      - Metropolitan Milwaukee Association of Commerce, 2004-2011 (Box 198, Folder 12)
      - Milwaukee 7, 2006-2008 (Box 198, Folder 13)
      - Milwaukee Addiction Treatment Initative (MATI), 2008 (Box 198, Folder 14)
      - Milwaukee Area Technical College (MATC), 2004-2010 (Box 198, Folder 15)
      - Milwaukee Brewers/Miller Park, 2004 (Box 198, Folder 16)
      - Milwaukee, City of, 2008 (Box 198, Folder 17)
      - Milwaukee Committment, 2004 (Box 198, Folder 18)
      - Milwaukee Connector, 2006 (Box 198, Folder 19)
      - Milwaukee, County of, 2006 (Box 198, Folder 20)
      - Milwaukee Idea, 2004-2009 (Box 198, Folder 21)
      - Milwaukee Initiative Plan, 2010 (Box 198, Folder 22)
      - Milwaukee Partnership Academy
        - 2004-2010 (Box 198, Folder 23-24)
        - Literacy Strategy, 2001
        - Meetings, 2000-2004 (Box 198, Folder 25-32)
        - Miscellaneous Files and Correspondence, 2001
      - Milwaukee Public Library, 2006-2010 (Box 198, Folder 33)
      - Milwaukee Public Schools, 2004-2006 (Box 198, Folder 34)
      - Mueller Communication, 2004-2008 (Box 198, Folder 35)
      - Multi-Cultural Affairs, 2004-2008 (Box 198, Folder 36)
      - Mumps, 2008 (Box 222, Folder 3)
      - Music, Department of, 2004-2005 (Box 198, Folder 37)
      - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), 2004-2008 (Box 199, Folder 1)
      - National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA)
        - 2004-2011 (Box 199, Folder 2)
        - Accreditation, 2007-2009 (Box 199, Folder 3)
        - Division 1 Certification Project Management Plan, 2007 (Box 199, Folder 4)
      - National Science Foundation, 2005-2010 (Box 199, Folder 5)
      - National Survey of Student Engagement, 2008 (Box 199, Folder 6)
      - Neighborhood Issues, 2003-2007 (Box 199, Folder 7)
      - Non-Santiago Correspondence, 2003-2004
      - Norris Health Center, 2004, 2007 (Box 199, Folder 8)
      - North Central Association (NCA) Reaccreditation, 2003-2009 (Box 199, Folder 9)
      - Northwest Quadrant, 2011 (Box 199, Folder 10)
      - Nursing, College of, 2004-2010 (Box 199, Folder 11-12)
      - Ombuds Council, 2007 (Box 199, Folder 13)
      - Open Forum on Educational Rights, 2010
      - Pabst Downtown Development Site, 2006 (Box 199, Folder 14)
      - Pandemic Flu Conference, 2006 (Box 222, Folder 4)
      - Partnerships and Innovations, 2005, 2009 (Box 199, Folder 15)
      - Past Chancellors Photographs, undated (Box 199, Folder 16)
      - Peace Studies, 2005 (Box 199, Folder 17)
      - Peck School of the Arts, 2004-2010 (Box 199, Folder 18)
      - Percent for Art, 2004-2005 (Box 199, Folder 19)
      - Philosophy, Department of, 2004 (Box 199, Folder 20)
      - Photos, 2004-2005
      - Physical Environment Committee, 2003-2011 (Box 199, Folder 21)
      - Physics, Department of, 2004-2006 (Box 199, Folder 22)
      - Plan 2008, 2004-2008 (Box 199, Folder 23)
      - Plenary, 2004-2005 (Box 199, Folder 24)
      - Police, 2003-2009 (Box 199, Folder 25)
      - Political Advisory Committee, 2008-2011 (Box 199, Folder 26)
      - Political Science, Department of, 2006 (Box 199, Folder 27)
      - Potawatomi Bingo Casino, 2005-2009 (Box 199, Folder 28)
      - Pre-College Academy, 2004-2011 (Box 199, Folder 29)
      - Psychology, Department of, 2009-2011 (Box 199, Folder 30)
      - Public Health
        - Community Advisory Council, 2007 (Box 199, Folder 31)
        - Planning for an Accredited School of Public Health at UWM, 2006 (Box 199, Folder 32)
        - School of
          - 2005-2009 (Box 199, Folder 33-35)
          - 2006-2008
      - Public Instruction, Department of, 2004 (Box 199, Folder 36)
      - Public Policy Forum, 2003-2011 (Box 199, Folder 37)
      - Public Policy Institute/Argosy Foundation, 2004-2008 (Box 199, Folder 38)
      - Publicity Materials, 2004-2011
      - Puerto Rico, 2007 (Box 199, Folder 39)
      - Recruitment and Outreach, 2004, 2010 (Box 199, Folder 40)
      - Regents, Board of, 2003-2009 (Box 199, Folder 41)
      - Research Catalyst Grant Program, 2010 (Box 199, Folder 42)
      - Research Foundation, 2006-2010 (Box 199, Folder 43)
      - Research Growth Initiative, 2006 (Box 199, Folder 44)
      - Research Incentive Grants Program, 2010 (Box 199, Folder 45)
      - Research Jobs Initiative, 2010 (Box 199, Folder 46)
      - Research Profile, 2001-2006 (Box 200, Folder 1)
      - Sandburg Residence Hall, 2004-2007 (Box 200, Folder 2)
      - Scholarships, 2004-2010 (Box 200, Folder 3)
      - Science Bag, 2004-2011 (Box 200, Folder 4)
      - Search and Screen Committees
        - Dean of College of Letters and Science, 2010 (Box 200, Folder 5)
        - Dean of Lubar School of Business, 2007-2008 (Box 200, Folder 6)
        - Dean of the School of Continuing Education, 2004-2005 (Box 200, Folder 7)
        - Dean of the School of Information Studies, 2004 (Box 200, Folder 8)
        - General, 2003-2008 (Box 200, Folder 9)
        - Vice Chancellor for Development, 2008 (Box 200, Folder 10)
        - Vice Chancellor for Finance and Administration, 2005-2008 (Box 200, Folder 11)
        - Vice Chancellor for Research and Dean of Graduate School, 2004-2007 (Box 200, Folder 12)
        - Vice Chancellor for Student Affairs, 2005-2006, 2010 (Box 200, Folder 13)
      - Secretary of the University
        - 2005-2009 (Box 200, Folder 14)
        - Search, 2006 (Box 200, Folder 15)
      - Segregated Fees, 2007-2008 (Box 200, Folder 16)
      - Shaked, Abe and Babs, 2006 (Box 200, Folder 17)
      - Shaw Professorship Program, 2004, 2011 (Box 200, Folder 18)
      - Smoking Policy, 2003-2008 (Box 200, Folder 19)
      - Social Welfare, School of, 2003-2010 (Box 200, Folder 20)
      - Southwestern Wisconsin Applied Technology Logo, undated (Box 200, Folder 21)
      - State Employee Combined Campaign (SECC), 2003-2007 (Box 200, Folder 22)
      - Strategic Research Development Program, 2005 (Box 200, Folder 23)
      - Student Accessibility Center, 2004-2011 (Box 200, Folder 24)
      - Student Affairs, Division of, 2004-2010 (Box 200, Folder 25)
      - Student Association, 2003-2004 (Box 200, Folder 26-27)
      - Student Correspondence, 2005-2011 (Box 200, Folder 28)
      - Student Demonstration Review, 2010 (Box 200, Folder 29)
      - Student Life, Office of, 2007-2008 (Box 200, Folder 30)
      - Student Misconduct, 2002-2010 (Box 203, Folder 4-5)
      - Student Organizations, General, 2006-2010 (Box 200, Folder 31)
      - Task Force on Internationalization, 2009 (Box 200, Folder 32)
      - Taxpayer's Bill of Rights (TABOR), 2004 (Box 200, Folder 33)
      - TechStar
        - Board of Directors Meeting, 2004 (Box 200, Folder 34)
        - Financial Support, 2003-2004 (Box 200, Folder 35)
      - Tuition and Fees, Non-Resident
        - 2003-2010 (Box 200, Folder 36)
        - 2004-2011 (Box 200, Folder 37)
      - Tuition Differential, 2010 (Box 200, Folder 38)
      - U.S. Department of Education, 2005-2009 (Box 200, Folder 39)
      - U.S. News and World Report, 2007 (Box 200, Folder 40)
      - United Community Center, 2003-2006 (Box 200, Folder 41)
      - United Way, 2004 (Box 200, Folder 42)
      - University Committee, 2003-2009 (Box 200, Folder 43)
      - University Corporation of Atmospheric Research, 2003-2011 (Box 200, Folder 44)
      - University Information Technology Services (UITS), 2004-2009 (Box 200, Folder 45)
      - University Relations and Communications, 2005-2007 (Box 200, Folder 46)
      - University Safety and Assurances, 2004-2011 (Box 200, Folder 47)
      - Urban Initiatives and Research, Center for, 2004-2006 (Box 200, Folder 48)
      - Urban Serving Universities, 2005-2006 (Box 200, Folder 49)
      - Urban Studies Program, 2006 (Box 200, Folder 50)
      - UW Colleges, 2003-2007 (Box 200, Folder 51)
      - UW Extension, 2004-2010 (Box 200, Folder 52)
      - UW System
        - Academic Affairs, 2004-2009 (Box 200, Folder 53)
        - Audit Staffing, 2004-2005 (Box 200, Folder 54)
        - President, 2004-2010 (Box 200, Folder 55)
      - Valued Eccentrics, 2006 (Box 201, Folder 1)
      - Vilas Professor/Vilas Trust, 2004-2010 (Box 201, Folder 2)
      - Water Council, 2009-2011 (Box 201, Folder 3)
      - Water Institute, 2004-2010 (Box 201, Folder 4)
      - Waukesha County Technical Institute, 2004 (Box 201, Folder 5)
      - Waukesha Merger Possibility, 2005 (Box 201, Folder 6)
      - WE Energies, 2004-2011 (Box 201, Folder 7)
      - Well City-Milwaukee, 2007-2008 (Box 201, Folder 8)
      - Wisconsin Center for the Advancement of Postsecondary Education (WISCAPE), 2004 (Box 201, Folder 9)
      - Wisconsin Idea Fellows, 2004 (Box 201, Folder 10)
      - Wisconsin Manufacturers and Commerce, 2008 (Box 201, Folder 11)
      - Wisconsin Planning Grant, 2009 (Box 201, Folder 12)
      - Wisconsin, State of, 2004-2009 (Box 201, Folder 13)
      - Wisconsin Women in Higher Educational Leadership (WWHEL), 2003-2004 (Box 201, Folder 14)
      - WiSys Technology Foundation, 2006-2007 (Box 201, Folder 15)
      - WUWM, 2004-2006 (Box 201, Folder 16)
      - Zelazo Center, 2011 (Box 201, Folder 17)
      - Zoo Interchange, 2009 (Box 201, Folder 18)
    - Event Files, 2004-2010
      Files relating to the public and private events at which Chancellor Santiago spoke or otherwise presided. These files usually contain a brief summary of the events in question, the speeches given by the Chancellor at the event, and copies of any presentation made. Most of these files pertain to routine events, such as the annual faculty/staff awards ceremony, presentations to the Faculty Senate and the UW Board of Regents, background information on Santiago's WUWM appearances, and the Winter and Spring commencement addresses. Santiago also spoke on a regular basis to local organizations, such as the Murray Hill Neighborhood Association, the Milwaukee Press Club, and various Rotary clubs around the Milwaukee area; most of these presentations served to promote the activities of UWM in the community.
      In addition to routine events, Santiago also spoke at or prepared background information for a number of one-time or irregularly-occurring events of potential interest to researchers, including:
      Prominent speakers at UWM, including Rigoberta Menchu Tum, Cornel West, Senator Herb Kohl, Joe Biden, Governor Jim Doyle, and Mayor Tom Barrett.
      Special events on or near campus, such as the rally supporting the Elite Eight appearance of the 2005 Men's Basketball team, UWM representation at the Wisconsin State Fair, UWM Night at Miller Park and at Milwaukee Bucks games, retirement ceremonies for a number of long-time UWM employees, and dedication of various new campus facilities.
      Information on international relationships and trips, including visits to Israel, Japan, China, and Poland and interinstitutional agreements that emerged from those visits.
      Responses to student unrest on campus, including reports on a number of campus protests and documents monitoring coverage of the protests on blogs, social media, and local news.
      Many of the event files have both a paper and electronic version. The paper versions of the files often include margin notes written by Santiago or other staff and thus may more accurately reflect the content of the speech or presentation actually delivered. The electronic files may include documents not easily reproduced in paper form, such as associated spreadsheets and charts, PowerPoint presentations, or audio-visual materials related to the event in question.
      - 2004 (Box 214)
      - 2004-2005 (Box 215)
      - 2006-2007 (Box 216)
      - 2008-2009 (Box 217)
      - 2009-2010 (Box 218)
  - 8. Lovell Administration Records, 2010-2014
    - Health, 2011 (Box 222, Folder 5)
    - Incentive Grant Program, 2013-2014 (Box 222, Folder 6)
    - Innovation Park, 2010-2011 (Box 222, Folder 7)
- Certificates and Proclamations, 2011, Accession 2011-016; 6 cubic ft. (6 boxes); Additions of certificates and proclamations from 2011. Most of these are congratulatory certificates sent on the occasion of Michael Lovell's inauguration as chancellor. There are also a few proclamations from local and state officials in Chancellor Lovell's honor.
- Personnel Files, 2012, Accession 2012-003; 2 cubic ft. (2 boxes); Additions of personnel, grievance, and complaint files closed in 2012.
- Personnel Files, 1990-1999, Accession 2012-054; .2 cubic ft. (1 box); Additions of personnel files, 1990-1999.
- Event Files, 2010-2014, Accession 2014-005; 6,056 digital files; Additions of event files dating from 2010 to 2014. Contains records of events attended by or of interest to Chancellor Michael Lovell, including briefing sheets, correspondence, presentation files, photographs, and videos. Of particular interest is video of the 2011 Act 10 rallies held on campus in February of that year.
  A preliminary file list of the electronic files is available in the archives. Please see an archivist for additional information.
- Subject Files, 2010-2014, Accession 2014-012; 328 digital files; Additions of subject files, dating from 2010 to 2014, maintained by Michael Lovell in his role as UWM Chancellor. Includes drafts and final copies of Lovell's plenary addresses, testimony to the Wisconsin State Legislature, presentations to the UW System Board of Regents and other officials, and other public writings and presentations created by and delivered by Lovell during his time as chancellor.
- Background/Subject Files, 1998-2014, Accession 2014-019; 15,670 digital files; Additions of background/subject files created by Brad Stratton for Chancellors Zimpher, Santiago, and Lovell, dating from 1998 to 2014. These files were either compiled at time of creation as reference for the action taken by the Chancellor's Office or as background for future action by the office. Included are files on student protests from 1998 to 2012, Campus and Academic Planning, neighborhood relations, budget, grant, and research reports and preparatory material, partnerships with other Milwaukee institutions and universities world-wide, and Chancellors' official communications with campus on various issues. Also included are publicity materials for the university, including images and videos.